And I hate to sound like a hater, cuz
I'm not. I hope everybody eventually
finds their stride in what works for
them.
But it's all the same.
>> Every real estate agent is posting the
exact same content. The same market
updates, the same just listed, the same
old boring tips that nobody watches.
>> I saw a video that a good friend of mine
who's a realtor did, and I got angry.
>> Matt Thornburg was sick of it, too. So,
he stopped. He found the single easiest
type of content to create that almost
nobody is doing.
>> It's It's very simple to make, man. All
my business comes from open houses and
social media. And And that's it.
>> Within his first month, clients started
coming directly to him, and his posts
were going viral.
>> I remember getting my first lead from
social media and just being like, "Oh,
this is like this easy?"
>> And it's I think it's at 60,000 views
now.
>> Now, it happens every single week that
clients are coming to him. And in this
interview, he breaks down the exact
format
>> For anybody that wants to make content
out there, make content in the morning.
Make an Instagram folder and call it R
and D.
>> And why it works precisely because
everybody else is ignoring it. All
right, Matt. So, I'm excited because
this is a a very special day near and
dear to my heart, a day that I've been
waiting ages for, which is the fact that
you are crushing content. So, you've
been on the channel before, and we
talked all things open houses and what
you've been able to do. And I'll link
that episode below because you are doing
six figures a year from open houses in a
way that I think many agents have not
considered, and it works incredible.
But, we're going to dive into all things
content. So, before we start diving in,
give some context as to, you know, who
you are, where you're from, but also
what led you to this journey as somebody
that is such a master at scripting,
prospecting, open the traditional way to
the point where you are now seeing
unbelievable results from content.
>> Yeah, that's a good question.
Um
I'm a rebel. I I don't like rules. I
don't like structure. It's why I can't
work for anybody else.
Um
and I I tend to go against the grain. I
tend to like if everybody's doing
something one way, I'm like, nah, I want
to do it this way.
Um
I had a baby to almost 2 years ago now.
Um and
I wanted to focus on different aspects
of the business. I saw the priority
shift. I've always been a hustler. I've
always just like work, work, work as
much as I need to to make it happen. And
my wife had always been a very awesome
supporter and partner of that. That
dynamic changed when we brought a little
one into the picture. It was like, hey,
we need more time from dad. And I and I
wanted to be there more. My mentality
shifted. I didn't want to work, you
know, 10-hour days, 12-hour days,
whatever. I wanted to be able to be
like, hey, let me bang out the most
important needle moving work and then
spend the rest of the time with my
family, right? Like the priority shifted
for myself.
And about 2 months ago,
I saw a video that a good friend of mine
who's a realtor did and I got angry. I
was like, I
you know, I was just like,
this it's the same it's the same thing.
It's literally was my response. I'm
like, it's the same your video, their
video, my video, every realtor is making
the same content. And I'm tired of
making it. It It infuriated me when I
went to go make my next real estate
video. I was like,
I don't like it. I'm not enjoying this
walk-through, putting the suit on.
That's not who I am anymore. I used to
wear suits like every single day. Now
I'm in a V-neck every day.
Um
and it just felt inauthentic. And I just
did just broke. I'm like, I'm done. I'm
not doing it that way anymore. I'm going
to do what I want to do. I love my city.
I love this city. I've been to every
single state in the United States. I've
been to most major cities in the United
States, and there's a lot of cool ones,
man. I love New Orleans. I love Chicago.
There's some really cool places around,
but there's no place, I firmly believe
in my heart, there's no place in the
world like San Diego. And I absolutely
love this city, and I was just like, you
know what? I'm just going to start
making content about my city because I
love it and I'm passionate about it. And
I also know that what I've been doing,
what building this business with open
houses, and open houses are phenomenal.
They're a great lead generation source.
If you go back to that video, you'll
you'll know I say to people that are out
there that are like, "Oh, open houses
don't work." It's like, "Well, you're
not doing enough of them." If you really
want When I wanted to make them my
business, I did four or five a week. Now
that I have a daughter and I have
different priorities, I'm 40 now, I
don't want to do four or five open
houses a week. I don't I do two or three
a week now, and even that I'm like, I
don't want to do that. I've been doing
it for 10 years. I don't I don't want to
work every weekend. I want to take my
girl to the zoo or the beach or I want
to spend family time on the weekend. So,
I had to think about like, how can I
shift? How can I bring my personality,
which I think is a very big thing in
this business, with my ability to
communicate and present it in a
different way, something I'm actually
passionate about. And just create, you
know, that neon sign behind me that says
connection for a big reason. I I believe
in connection above all else, and I'm
like, so how can I create connection in
a different way outside of an open
house, outside of something I'm tied to
physically, where I can do this
anywhere? So, if I want to go to, you
know, we've got River House. If I want
to go out to the river and work for I
can still work for the weekend and take
the boat out, like
And it just kind of clicked. I was like,
I need to just start making content
about my city, about being passionate
about it. My personality is going to
show through. It's different than pretty
much, you know, I've only seen like two
or three other realtors that do this.
Um, and at least in my city, I've only
seen two or three that do it. Um, and
it's worked out. The last couple of
months have been fun.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, man. It's it's crazy because
that's one of the traps that I find a
lot of agents fall victim to is like
they struggle so much with consistency
because they're trying to do something
that they genuinely don't enjoy doing.
And it's exhausting. Like and
>> [clears throat]
>> I can speak from experience cuz I think
you and I both went through this where
you know, for years I my first couple of
years of YouTube videos, I number one
was trying to be like a YouTube
personality and and I changed who I was
because I thought you had to be this way
on this platform. And so every time I
got to I went to record,
it just didn't feel authentic. It didn't
feel genuine. And I wasn't proud of it.
And I but I just thought like you got to
do it anyway, so just like suck it up
and get it done.
>> [snorts]
>> And the year that I changed and started
being authentically myself and doing it
my way, my business blew up. And I had
way more fun. It didn't feel like a job.
It felt like a passion project. And and
everybody started to connect with it.
And that's where I think
we're we're in this unique industry
where so many people are just trying to
model
others in different markets instead of
looking within and saying like, who
genuinely am I? Like any person that
I've ever seen, you know, there's
Shawnee in our group and and she's like
an Atlanta woman, big energy, big
personality, and she lets that shine
through and crushes. Or there's so many
different examples of people that I've
seen who are just unapologetically
themselves
and that drives massive business with
the people that actually connect with
them. And that's the that's the best
part is like
if you're putting out content that's not
you
you will attract clients that don't
actually connect with you. And then you
start dealing with nightmare clients.
It's a lose-lose. You hate it, the
people hate it, your business struggles.
And so let's start to kind of unpack
what that content is because I love
watching all of your videos and I
genuinely watch them start to finish and
I don't give two shits about San Diego.
And so but but I'm like it's so
interesting. I'm like if I was ever to
go there, which I have been and loved it
to be honest. It was best fish tacos
I've ever had in my life. Um
but what are you creating? Like let's
walk through this process of maybe what
were you creating before? What are you
really leaning into now?
>> Yeah, good question. So before I
obviously I do a lot of open houses, so
I'm in a lot of different properties.
Before I was doing a lot of like
property tours where like you know, and
the full setup like very professionally
dressed, setting the tripod up, having
the the gimbal that follows you and the
you know, and
trying to be super professional and and
it's funny because
I can speak well and I know how to
connect with people and everything, but
I'm and you can hear from my vocal
inflections and tonality like I'm from
the hood. Like I'm not I I'm a hard
worker. I am a professional, but I'm not
like that buttoned up
like you know, let's talk about our
401ks over a golf like morning. Like
nah, that's not me, man. And and so
that's the type of content I was making.
I was making a lot of property
walk-throughs. Um
I used to do years ago I used to do this
thing called a minute with Matt that
actually like very the very beginning of
I think video the video era in the
social media like started to get some
traction, but that content wouldn't work
nowadays. It had B-roll and stuff in it.
And I you know, I was making content
for lack of a better word, I was making
content that everybody else makes. That
all other realtors. If you look at any
realtors Instagram or social media or
YouTube, whatever, TikTok.
And I hate to sound like a hater cuz I'm
not. I hope everybody eventually finds
their stride and what works for them.
But it's all the same, man. It's all the
same. It's all you know, you're standing
in front of a property and the freaking
giant text comes in and it's like behind
you and it's like I've seen nine of
these videos today, man. Like it's very
rarely are they shot in a way that is
actually impressive. Very rarely are the
people letting their personality show
through. You know, they're speaking, I
think, in a way that they think they're
supposed to be perceived as
professionals.
Um
and I just didn't like it. That's the
content I was making. It's funny if you
go back and you if you go back in my
Instagram, you can actually see where
the shift was. It's a very clear like
you can scroll down and see, oh, this is
when it changed. And literally like two
videos before I was, you know, we've
been studying, we're in this amazing
group, we have all these supporters.
I've been studying like different ways
to make videos, visual hooks, auditory
hooks, etc. And there's a couple of
videos where I'm doing like property
walk-throughs and in the very beginning
shot, I'm like upside down. I'm like
laying on a bed or I'm laying on the
ground and I'm upside down and I'm like,
oh yeah, it's going to make people stop
cuz I'm upside down. Why is this guy
upside down? It's terrible. It's so
terrible. It's so bad. I laugh at it
now.
Um and it just wasn't authentic and just
wasn't connecting. And
I I met somebody, actually. This is very
funny. I got invited to a networking
event,
>> [snorts]
>> a really high-end networking event here
in San Diego with super top producers.
Like everybody in the room is is, you
know, I think 10 million in productivity
minimum uh uh annually and uh
the people that we're speaking are are
way excess of that, you know, you're
talking people that are doing 100
million in productivity a year. And I
met somebody that does what I'm doing
now in in here in San Diego. Very cool
dude, very chill, very open-minded, very
non-gatekeeping, very like sat down and
had a great like 10-minute talk with me.
And it wasn't super it wasn't like, you
know, we didn't have an hour and a half
lunch and discuss every single thing,
but the 10-minute chat we had really
opened my eyes to like
his process and why he makes content the
way he does and he makes content very
similar to what I make. It's focused on
North County, San Diego, not I focus
more on the city center, that's where I
live and I and where I like to, you
know, live and operate and do business,
so I focus more here. Um but it just
opened my eyes to like a different way
of looking at content creation and
everything and um
and he literally told me he goes, "Bro,
like you have a great personality. Steal
what I'm doing and just do it your way."
And I I fully support that because I
tell other people the same thing. When
people are like, "Oh, I love what you're
doing." I'm like, "Bro, steal it. Steal
it and put yours Don't do it one word
for word, one for one. Take the idea and
make it your own. You know what I mean?
Like like we're not reinventing anything
here, you know?" Um
and and it just clicked with me, man,
and I made I made the first video that
was like this new style. I talked about
seven major development projects that
were going on around San Diego and I
think
it has 30 or 40,000 views now. Um and
then I just I just kept going. I was
like, "Every day I'm just going to make
a video and talk about what I love about
this city, either what I love about this
and and and here's like the the kicker.
It's all different. It's not exactly the
same every single time cuz like I'll
talk about San Diego history. I'll talk
about San Diego news. The video that I
made today is about another San Diego
development project. I'll talk about San
Diego
um
events, you know, like I do a Friday
post that just talks about here's what's
happening for the weekend. Like if you
don't have plans, here's what you can go
do, you know? I love this city.
>> [clears throat]
>> We this city it's so nuts when you think
about it. This city has the number one
sports pub in the United States, had is
the number one place to watch the sunset
in the United States. It's the most
relaxing city on Earth. We have the
number two best weather on Earth. Like
there's so much about this city that's
amazing. And people always talk trash,
oh it's so expensive, it's so expensive.
It's like yeah, but you get what you pay
for. A Camry is a great car, but there's
a reason it's 45 grand and a Bentley's
200.
>> Yeah.
>> San Diego's the Bentley, man. And it's
real easy for me to get passionate and
talk talk about that Bentley.
>> Mhm. Yeah, man. And And I think that's
what I love about it is like you can see
the passion come through. And like when
you're passionate, that connects with
people emotionally. Like that's
the At the end of the day with content,
the entire goal is to get people to
know, like, and trust you and be able to
genuinely connect with you on the
emotional level. Not surface level, not
transactional, but at the emotional
level. And anybody that I look up to,
anybody that I follow on content, and
anybody that's listening, you can
resonate and connect with this as well.
Anybody that you enjoy consuming content
from, you can tell that they are
passionate about what they're sharing,
whether it's in a creative space,
whether it's in an educational space,
whether it's home cooking tips, like
whoever you connect with, there's an
emotional attachment there because you
could tell they love it. And you love
it. And that connection is established.
But, you know, with that being said,
maybe give some insight on
what this type of content is. And then
I've got a couple questions about the
the workflow side because
>> Yeah.
>> you know, the the average agent that I
see that is talking about their city,
they're doing it in
the same way everybody else is, which is
they've got their, you know, they're
usually like either walking down a
street with somebody filming them
talking about something that a chat GPT
told them to talk about or they are just
sitting in a little office and with not
much excitement. Like, what does your
content look like? Quick pause. If
you're watching this feeling stuck,
overwhelmed by all the noise, tired of
chasing leads, unsure of how to close
consistent deals every month with
clients coming directly to you for free,
I want you to know something. That's
exactly where the agent you're listening
to right now was before we started
working together. And if you want the
same support, the same system, and
access to all of my social media and AI
training, daily live mastermind calls,
and direct mentorship, completely free,
no extra split, and no extra cost, click
the link in the description to book a
call. We'll talk about partnering
together so that you could be the next
success story that we're telling on my
YouTube channel. Now, let's get back
into the interview.
>> Yeah, good question. It's talking head
content. Um and to be clear, it was like
a natural evolution. So, I'm at my desk
now. I have a 120-year-old Victorian. Um
sometimes there's quirks with it like,
you know, it's old electrical and
you know, I'll get glitches in my camera
or other weird things just like that. I
don't know if you saw that.
>> [laughter]
>> Um uh because this house is 120 years
old, but I'm in my I'm in my my office
right now. And my phone sits right here
on a stand that points right at me.
And for
I don't know, two or three years now, uh
when I really started dialing in my CRM,
which is actually when I joined the Wolf
Pack. I was never a CRM guy before that.
I would make videos on my phone to send
to clients. If I call and they don't
answer, I don't send a text, I send a
video every single time. If I call and
they don't answer. And it sits almost at
the same exact angle that I make my
talking head videos at. And so, the it
just clicked. I'm like, I'm already
talking to my phone. I might as well
just talk to my phone and instead of
talking to one person, talk to
everybody, right? So, it's talking head
content, right?
Um
it's it's very simple to make, man. I go
through like um
>> With the green screen app, right?
>> Yeah, I dude, I use CapCut. I use
CapCut. Um I edit right in CapCut. It
I'm able to um
uh you know, remove the background and
just put what I want behind it. Um and I
it's funny um even the other people in
this city that make this content, the
similar content to mine,
I've had people reference them and and
and mention them to me and say that they
enjoy my content better.
And I think it's because I allow my
personality to shine through. Like I'm
I'm loud. I'm a loud person. I accept
it. I'm comfortable with who I am. If
you don't like loud noises, we're
probably not going to be friends. Like I
accept it.
A lot of these people that are making
content about these cities and they're
talking about things, they're very
monotone. There's not a lot of emotion.
There's not a lot of of expression. I'm
the opposite. I'm talking to my phone,
but I'm
in my mind, I'm talking to friends,
right? Like I literally put myself in
the mindset, I'm like, I'm talking to my
friends right now. And like it's just so
easy to be so animated and so passionate
and expressive, but it's just talking
head content, man. I literally like
every day when I'm I make a video every
day. Every day and sometimes I make two
a day. Every day I'll I'll pull First I
go to I go just go Google San Diego news
and I just look for interesting stuff
that has happened. I like to focus on
positivity more than negativity, which
is difficult because everybody focuses
on negativity, so there's a lot more
negative news. Um but some of my best
videos like uh there's a a Native
American woman from San Diego who's got
this beauty brand that's uh based off uh
Native American knowledge with um acorn
oil and stuff like that. Who by the way
is amazing. We're developing a
relationship now. We're going to see
what we can do together. She's amazing.
Like she
I open San Diego news and one of like I
had to scroll down and I this article
was not being blasted on the front page
or nothing, but she made the Times 100
list of like most influential beauty
products or something. And she got
picked up to like so I forget the
number, but like a a large number of
Ritz-Carlton spas. And I'm just like
that's freaking cool, man. Like that is
a really cool positive thing to talk
about. And so I made a video out about
it and it's I think it has 60,000 views
now. You know, like I just like
supporting cool positive fun stuff and
when it when it connects with this city,
it's very easy to do because I love this
city.
>> 100%.
>> Funny enough, actually, sorry, I'm going
to talk over you. I have this tagline
saying I love this freaking city.
Yeah. And it just naturally came like I
didn't plan that branding with ChatGPT
and Googling. I didn't plan that. I just
said it in a video and then I was like
oh, that's it. Like I love this freaking
city. That's it. Like I'm just going to
end every video like that. Sorry. I
talked over you.
>> No, it's it's so cool, man. Like and I
think like there's that age-old like
it's it's so cliché, but like
anybody in the OG days of content like
the narrative was like you want to be
the mayor of your town. Like you just
want to be somebody that's a local
resource that talks about your market
because
what I find is that the the average
agent is so
consumed by lead generation that their
entire thought process every single time
they put out a piece of content is can
this generate leads without realizing
that the name of the game is not leads,
it's attention.
And if you get enough attention, the
leads follow. The leading indicator of
leads is attention. It's mass top of
funnel people to get to know you even
exist. But if you don't have people that
know you exist, when you put out a lead
generation focused video like how to buy
a house, how to sell a house, nobody's
listening. Nobody cares, right? And so
that's where I think you've done so well
at being able to say, I just want people
to know who I am. I'm already passionate
about this. I'm going to share it. And
the best lesson that I hope people take
away from this
is what you said about just talking to a
friend.
Because the content that connects the
best is when
like people have to realize that even
though you're sharing a video with
thousands of people,
there is one individual on the other
side of that screen that's listening.
You have to speak to them. And usually
it's your ideal target avatar, somebody
that would enjoy working with you. And
so oftentimes people are creating
content thinking that it's for the
masses, but in reality it's for one
person.
And that's where I always like to use
the analogy
that like if you look at anybody that
you really connect with, maybe it's Tony
Robbins or maybe it's Gary V or anybody
that you look up to and you listen to,
you always feel like they're speaking
directly to you.
Even though they're speaking to millions
of people. Why? Because you're their
target avatar. So, when they're
recording that video,
they feel like they're speaking to you,
not this huge audience. And that's what
I love that you've done about this to
allow that personality to come through,
because that's one of the things I think
people struggle with the most. And so,
with that being said,
it one of the things that I love aside
from the fact that you're
super genuine in your content,
is your consistency. Which is what so
many people struggle with is the finally
find a format that works for them,
but it's
it they have no workflow to the point
where it's an exhaustive effort to
record. So, maybe take us through a
week. You could you kind of mentioned
CapCut, but like from start to finish,
what would a week look like in terms of
recording, editing, finding the video
topics, to then staying consistent?
>> Yeah, uh very good question. Consistency
is like the hobgoblin of of achievement,
right? Like, [laughter]
it's so funny cuz even myself I've
struggled with consistency so much in
the past. And I have
I have mental health issues. Like, I
have wild ADHD. Like, insanely like, to
the point where the the doctors are
literally like, "This is like up there."
Like, it's intense. Um
uh and so, like, I struggle with
consistency probably even more than
other people.
Um I found as far as consistency goes,
keeping everything super simple is very
important.
You also have to find what works for
you, right? There's all different types
of like time management strategies and
productivity strategies. And like, I
used to try to batch content, record
like four or five videos at once, and
then edit them. And to be honest, that
just doesn't work for me. It it works
for some people, great for them. It I I
think I just have too intense of ADHD,
and I get distracted, and I have too
much going on where I'm just like, I
don't remember which video and blah blah
blah, whatever, and I don't have a giant
team behind me yet to keep me focused.
So,
for me, I literally make a a new video
every day, and I start the process every
single day. So, like, I dumbed it down.
I dumbed it down. All of my business
comes from two avenues. Well, I get some
from my sphere and referrals, but really
all of my business comes from open
houses and social media, and and that's
it. And so, in my mind, I'm like, those
are the only two things that you need to
focus on, nothing else. I think a lot of
agents, when it comes to consistency, a
lot of agents allow themselves to be
distracted by too many things. I need to
be on every single call, I need to be on
every single training, I need to door
knock and do open houses and cold call
and make content. So, no, man.
Keep it real simple. Keep it real
simple. My day is literally organized in
two pieces and two pieces only.
I have the mornings where I create
content and the afternoons where I
connect with people. That's it. That's
it, man. So, I wake up at 5:30 in the
morning, uh which is not quite as early
as you wake up, I know, but I
>> [laughter]
>> I don't know and to be honest, I don't
know if I want to push it more than
5:30. But, I wake up at 5:30, I take
care of myself first, because if I don't
take care of myself, I can't show up for
everybody else. So, I read, I don't
touch my phone for the first half an
hour to an hour that I'm awake. I read,
I drink coffee, I drink water, hydrate
first, I start with an uh apple cider
vinegar and and lemon uh water,
um and then drink coffee, feed my mind,
make sure I work out, go into my day
physically fit, mentally fit, taking
care of myself, meditate before I go
into my day with affirmations.
And then, content is super simple, man.
Uh number one, I check the news first. I
I literally Google important or
impactful San Diego news. I just Google
it. I don't use AI, anything. I go to
different news sites. I look for
anything that is positive first. I
really want to support really cool
positivity first. Um and then
if I can't find anything that's
important and positive first, then I'll
look for just like city news, new
developments. Developments are always
like a a good one to make a video about,
developments, restaurant openings, bar
openings, anything that's like that I
would be interested in because then I
know that's going to connect with people
that I'm going to connect with, right?
And then from there, it's very simple,
man. I have um I use AI. Uh actually,
I'll add another tidbit.
I also have an Instagram folder that I
highly recommend anybody that's out
there that's making content. Make an
Instagram folder and call it R and D.
And R and D doesn't stand for research
and development. It stands for rip off
and duplicate, okay?
Don't reinvent the wheel. It's already
done. Like and keep in mind like I said
before, don't do it one for one. Don't
be a jerk and like recreate word for
word the video that somebody else did.
Don't do that. But if somebody else made
a cool video about a cool topic, you can
recreate that video in your authentic
way in your own voice, and that's okay,
man, because the thing is
there's so many people, and there's
people that that person connected with
because the way they said it is going to
connect with them, and then the way you
say it is going to connect with other
people. You're going to find your tribe.
So, I will check the news, and then if I
can't find anything in the news, I'll go
to my R and D folder. When I'm engaging
in social media, and I see something
that's cool or there might be an like a
topic there, I save it to that folder.
And then that's where I go back to for
my ideas. Um I also have like I have a
running note on my iPhone. Like if I'm
just out in the in the world and I see
something like, you know, when I'm
walking or
out doing appointments, I'll be like,
"Oh, that's that's a video topic,
right?" So, like I have those three
avenues that I'll get my ideas from.
Um
and then it's very simple. I have a AI
create everything for me, man. I uh I
have very dialed in prompts about how I
want the script, how I want the the
descriptions and captions and
everything. Um I have my own
communication style already dialed in
thanks to you. Your program helped me to
develop my entire like literally I have
a document just called my ad copy and
communication marketing communication
style. I have another document that's my
target avatar so that I know who I'm
targeting.
And then I have my brand guide, my
entire brand guide and so I attach all
three of these to every single document
so that the content is being created in
my authentic voice
and being targeted at the right people
that I'm going to connect with, right?
Here's a kicker, a little ninja pro tip
that I think a lot of people aren't
doing.
I don't use that script word for word. I
modify that script in my own voice. I'll
take that script, I'll read through it a
couple times and then I retype and
rewrite and fix things
to make it sound even more like myself
cuz AI is not going to be perfect and
also
that's where the personality comes in.
Like yeah, you can use AI as a tool to
like get you 90% of the way, 80% of the
way, but you got to dial it in yourself
because that's where the authenticity is
going to come through. In that video
about Ruth Ann is the woman behind
Native Beauty is the brand that Native
American brand.
She bought a building in the Gaslamp
here in San Diego. She's the first
Native American to ever buy a building
in in the Gaslamp in San Diego. And in
part of the video I say she bought the
building, y'all. She's killing it. Like
and that was just like off the cuff.
Like I just I just go off script and
just riff and let my build my
personality come through.
But so I use AI, I dial in everything, I
then
refine it per like manually refine it
myself.
And then I record right here at my desk
I on my phone. I have an iPhone 16 Pro
Max. I don't use a fancy camera. I do
have The funny part is I have fancy
cameras, but I use my phone.
>> [laughter]
>> It's so easy. Um and yes, I have lights
and stuff like that to make sure that
I'm lighted well, but in reality, you
just need a phone and an idea. That's
That's it. It's all you need. I record
on my phone. I edit in CapCut. I edit
myself. I know you're going to hate me
for saying that. I'm not at the point
yet, I think, where I'm ready to give up
control of the editing to an editor, and
I know that's another leverage uh
like a leverage roadblock or something
that I'm going to hit
probably pretty soon.
Uh but also turnaround to me is very
important. First of all, the reality is
like
finding an idea, making the video, and
getting it posted, when it's a
short-form talking head video,
I might not even eventually even need an
editor for that. Because in reality,
from the from having no idea to being
posted,
an hour to an hour and a half tops.
Tops. Absolutely tops. Right? Like it's
so easy because the editing is so
minimal.
And
and you're just you're not doing a lot
of crazy tricks. You want your authentic
authentic authentic voice and
personality to show through. So
literally, refine everything, record it,
throw it into CapCut,
throw some overlays, you know, whatever
I'm talking about, I want it to pop up
behind me, throw some overlays,
duplicate the layer with myself, remove
the background, it's done. That's it.
Post it. And then the other side of that
is like
something I didn't realize, I think,
when my social media started to take off
is how much time you have to spend
engaging. Yeah.
Because that's where the magic actually
happens. You're sitting there connecting
with people, making comments, responding
to messages. And that's something that I
still struggle with. Like I've got
I'll I'll you know, dude, I'll do I'll
have a video that'll do 3,000, 4,000,
5,000 views and next thing you know I
have 100 new followers and all these
messages and all these comments and it's
like, all right, I got to spend 2 hours
just sitting here just responding to
content, but that leads perfectly into
my afternoon block. I create the
content, post it in the morning, go have
my lunch, recharge a little bit over
lunch, and then in my afternoon block,
I'm connecting with people, I'm sending
messages, I'm responding to DMs, I'm
setting appointments, and literally all
my afternoon is for is for connecting
with people, usually DMs, my CRM, I
check check my CRM daily and see what I
need to follow up with, and then going
on appointments, you know,
meeting people out in the world and
that's it. And that's the simplicity
that it takes to be consistent.
I look at it I need to do I really need
to do three things. I need to create
content, connect with people, and go on
appointments, and that's it.
That's it, man.
>> 100%.
>> So, if you dial if you really dial in
what you're focused on and don't allow
yourself to be distracted, it's funny,
I'll get texts or calls from other
Wolfpack agents so they're like, hey
buddy, why weren't you on this call? And
I'm like, cuz that call didn't have
anything to do with my business. Or I'll
log onto a call and I'll be on it for 5
minutes and I'll realize, oh, this
doesn't have anything to do with my
business, I'm going to log off. People
allow themselves to be distracted,
especially newer agents. They've shiny
object syndrome, right? They're like,
you know, you see an agent on a call
who's doing 100 deals a year from cold
calling, and then you all of a sudden
want to cold call when it's nothing
you've ever wanted to do before in your
life and you're like, why why? Stop
getting distracted, man. Like, focus on
what you want to focus on, dial it into
the nines, and keep it simple. That's
it, man. Make content, like for anybody
that wants to make content out there,
structure your day like I do. Make
content in the morning because it's the
it's con like you want the thing that
you're going to have the most mental
resistance to to be the first thing you
got to do, right? Like so make the
content in the morning and then in the
afternoon, this is going to sound bad
maybe, but in the afternoon it's so easy
to just sit on your phone and respond to
comments. That is not hard at all.
And that's all I do, man. Sit on the
phone, respond to comments, follow, you
know, check my CRM, see who's in there
with notes and who I need to follow up
and set appointments and then go show
properties.
>> That's so cool and and I think like, you
know, it's so powerful even just talking
about your your process for ideation.
When you really boil it down, there are
multi-billion-dollar companies whose
entire job is to create the news for
that day.
And they've done the work for you. Like
it's not like we need to come up with
this innovative strategy of how to talk
about something nobody else has ever
talked about before. We are literally
just looking at what other people have
done all the hard work to find and then
putting our own authentic take on it.
Like it's just that simple and and I
like that you also talked about
engagement because
I think a lot of people have this
tendency to feel like social media
happens to magically be this one-way
street where you're looking for all this
engagement, but you're not giving any.
And that doesn't work, right? If
somebody's talking to you in person,
you're not just going to sit there and
not say anything back. You're going to
communicate. Like that is communication
in its simplest form and that's how real
estate is is being able to boil it down
to real conversations and like you said,
you know, being able to
I always think an agent should do some
form of lead generation for 3 hours a
day. Well,
the alternative of cold calling for 3
hours versus an hour to post a video and
2 hours to, you know, sit in a comfy
couch and engage, I'll choose that any
day. And the fact that it's not that
difficult says a lot. So I love that,
dude. And and so, you know, I've I've
seen you get a [__] ton of comments and
and that kind of leads to
How do you find people are engaging with
you to the point where they become a
real estate focused conversation?
Because sometimes what I see is people
start to put out content, they'll get a
little bit of engagement, but they can't
quite get it to the point where it's
like, "Okay, how do I If I'm just
talking about my city, how do I weave in
the fact that I'm a real estate agent?
Or how do I get them to the point of
becoming a client? What's that journey
look like or has it looked like for
you?"
>> Yeah, uh very good question, right?
Because I think there's not an obvious
bridge there, right? Especially like
if I'm talking about like, you know,
some random piece of history about San
Diego. Like I made a a video the other
day about the first mission, which is
how San Diego got its name and
everything. Like how does that translate
like,
you know, this this priest 200 and
something whatever years ago. How does
that translate to a real estate
conversation now?
First and foremost, I like to just put
small, really small CTAs in my in my
videos. And I have to be very conscious
about it. I don't want it to be super
salesy or pitchy. I just put things in
there like, "Hey, if you, you know, if
you love this city as much as I do and
want to make it home, there's a link in
my bio, you know?" Stuff like that,
where it's literally like as simple and
and chill of a sentence as
as uh possible.
Um but then you also have to look for
other opportunities, right? And that's
I think having, you know, we God, we've
talked about this on one of our
mastermind calls and not we personally,
I mean we as a the Wolfpack group. Um
looking for the opportunities, right?
Like when you're training your brain to
look for sales opportunities as a new
agent, you have to realize that
opportunities can come from anywhere.
Like you have, you know they can come
from standing in line at the grocery
store, sitting at a bar. It doesn't just
have to be an open house. Like you have
to look for these opportunities. So
I do the same thing in in comments and
and messages and stuff like that. First
I do use ManyChat. I use automation to
make sure that anytime I have a new
follower they get a message from me.
It's not a salesy message man. It's it's
a super short either or. It just says
something like
hey thanks for following along are you
just here for the content or are you
thinking about buying or selling in San
Diego?
Like that's it man. And I don't use any
flows after that. Every single message
that comes after that I manually respond
to. So
when that message goes out it's funny
98%
99% of the responses are like oh I'm
just here for the content. So I thank
them. Hey man thanks I'm glad you
enjoyed the content. I hope it helps you
enjoy our city a little bit more. Can
you do me a favor? If you hear of
anybody who's thinking about buying or
selling who you think would like my vibe
please send them my way.
Psychologically people are afraid to ask
for for favors. But in reality if you
study communication asking somebody for
a favor instead of doing a favor for
somebody or instead of offering help
asking somebody for a favor actually
really connects them with you. Like you
create a bond and a rapport. So I'm
creating connection by asking for this
favor and then I'm just being authentic
man. And wherever those messages go I
don't act salesy in it. I've had super
long conversations with strangers in my
DMs about the most random stuff.
Literally was talking to somebody
yesterday about downtown Chula Vista and
like these old places that used to exist
and aren't there and then made me think
about a memory from when I was in high
school and there you know you just I
just bring authenticity to it but also
ask right? Like I you have to ask for
the business, you know?
Um you know, hey, you know, are you are
you you know, if people will put oh, I
have a house already. Okay, how long you
been there? Is that you know, is that is
that your forever home in your dream
neighborhood?
Like let's talk about that, you know? So
I I think it's just having authentic
genuine conversations with people,
reminding people that this is what you
do, right? Like we we can't be
undercover agents. Like even if I'm
making a video that's about San Diego, I
still put that small reminder in there
that I'm an agent. And then engaging
with people and asking for the
opportunities, right? I I got my first
lead. I remember getting my first lead
from social media that actually turned
into a contract, right?
And just being like
oh, this is like this easy? Like
>> [laughter]
>> this like this was just a natural
conversation on social media. Like and
it just turned into a contract. I'm
like, okay, how do I replicate that?
Just have natural conversations with
people. Don't be salesy. People can
smell it a mile away. Don't be super
pitchy. Don't talk about yourself. Ask
questions and just engage.
And that's it, you know, look for where
you can provide value. I I've got a a
new agent. Actually, I posted in school.
Uh I don't know if you saw my post from
yesterday in school. Somebody had asked
yesterday on on our call about a
unresponsive leads. And I have a very
authentic way that I approach
unresponsive leads, right? Um
And the lead that I did it with
yesterday literally was like a lead from
Instagram that had sat down with
multiple realtors and did not want to
sit down with me. When I asked for the
appointment the first time, they were
like, you know, hey, is there any
pre-qualification that we can do
beforehand? Like I'm in sales also. I
understand discovery calls are like
important, but also like I've been he
literally said these words. He's like,
I've been on so many first dates with
realtors lately. He goes, "I've just I
just don't really want to meet another
one." And I sent a video message back
and I just said like explained my
approach. I was like, "Hey man, I can
send you a buyer's guide. I can send you
client testimonials and reviews. I go,
but here's the thing. This is how I
operate. This is where my mindset is.
And if that work if that sounds good to
you, we should grab coffee. If it
doesn't sound good to you, we're
probably not going to be a good fit. So,
you can tell me to screw off, right?
That authenticity like literally
bringing that approach to it landed me
the appointment. He goes, "You know
what? I respect it. Let's get coffee."
Now we're showing properties this
weekend.
>> [laughter]
>> It's It's just you just be authentic and
connect with people and look for ways
to be of value to people, you know?
Like don't don't ask for anything like
don't ask for a commitment without
offering something, you know? Like even
those people that I'm asking the favor
to send people that need to move my way,
I'm offering the content and the
knowledge about the city first. I'm
like, "Hey, here's this really cool
thing that I do. I hope you enjoy it. I
hope it helps you enjoy the city a
little more.
Now will you do me this favor?
You know?
>> So cool, dude. And And I think, you
know, that kind of leads to one of the
things that I was genuinely curious
about because you've got such a really
you've got such an extensive history in
terms of the skills that you've stacked
over the course of being in this
industry that I'm really curious to get
your insider or what your opinion is on
how communication
has helped with your content because you
are, you know, we've got another video
coming about this, but you are a master
communicator. You're incredible at
understanding the human language and
being able to be persuasive in a
value-driven way and and being able to
genuinely connect with people, not
taking these like super salesy rigid
scripts, but how do you find your
experience with traditional real estate
has kind of helped you in this new era
of what you're doing on the modern side.
>> Yeah, that's a very good question
because
uh
I think a lot of times people think that
DMs and social media like that the
normal rules don't apply, but they do
translate. They don't apply one-for-one,
but they do translate. And before I go
into that, let me say thank you first so
much. Those are very words. And what you
say about my ability to communicate, I
want people out there to know it's not
like God-given ingrained. I had to work
really hard at it. I'm from the hood.
Like I grew up very poor in a very
you know,
hard-headed environment. When I got into
this business, I did not communicate the
way that I communicate [laughter] now.
And it was if you would have heard me 10
years ago, it you would have been like
>> [laughter]
>> uh it was a lot of work, man. It was a
lot of work to develop the skills. I
knew that I had the ability to
communicate with people kind of
inherently. I'm personable and I will
talk to people, but I didn't have
I didn't have like a like
The way I look at at scripting and
frameworks and I like to call them
frameworks instead of scripting cuz I
think scripting
like it's a very old-school thing that a
lot of people don't understand really
and doesn't work in today's day and age.
I look at all these different language
tools and communication tools as just
tools in a tool belt. And the more that
I have, the more equipped I am to have a
productive conversation with somebody.
Every time I talk to an agent about
communication, I say, "Look,
your job communicating with people is to
is to be efficient with your time,
especially if you're in an open house
with 30 visitors. Like dude, how are you
going to know who you should focus on
and who you shouldn't focus on? And
don't get me wrong, I love the the nosy
neighbor who's lived in the neighborhood
for 40 years and knows everything, those
conversations are great, but there's no
need that you can serve there.
That's the bottom line. There's not a
need you can serve, and our job is to
have conversations to look for needs we
can serve. Our job is not to sell people
things they don't need or want. Our job
is to look for needs we can serve,
uncover needs in people that we can
serve, and then be valuable to them
accomplishing what they're trying to
accomplish. That's it, right?
The problem is so many times people lack
the skill set to communicate that. You
might know what you want to say or know,
you know, what how you feel, but you
don't know how to put it into words
effectively, right? So, I spent many,
many, many, many years in literally in a
in a communication
class
Monday through Friday, 7:00 a.m. to 8:00
I think it was 7:00 doesn't matter. It's
an hour every single morning. So, it was
a lot of years focusing on this.
That translates into social media
because psychologically the basis of
communication is still the same.
>> Mhm.
>> Like, whether it's a DM or video or
face-to-face conversation or phone call,
psychologically the basis of
communication is still the same. My
like, we'll take my script for
uh um reestablishing a connection with a
a an unresponsive lead. It's simple,
man. Hey Mike, it's Matt. I haven't
heard from you in a little bit. I just
want to make sure that I didn't
accidentally offend you or drop the ball
with you in any way.
Super simple, right? That works over a
phone call, over a video message, over a
DM. It works it's the same thing. It
works very, very well. And it works
because I'm not pointing a finger at
them. I'm not blaming them. I'm putting
the finger on me, actually, allowing
them a guilt-free excuse or way out to
acknowledge like, "Hey, man, I'm sorry.
It's not you. Life's been hectic." We
all know life's hectic. Like, it's an
easy thing, right? So,
the communication that I've developed
and worked on and built in face-to-face
conversations and phone conversations, I
did a lot of cold calling for a long
time. I don't do very much anymore, but
the basis of the communication, the
rules of the communication are still the
same. They still transfer.
>> 100%.
I love that, man. And and so,
you know, as we kind of pull this
together, that's what, you know, I
admire about you is that you, you know,
I always say that the most expensive
thing you can own is a closed mind. And
it's it's incredible to see that you've
been able to not only excel after years
of relentless hard work with one side of
business, but you're not getting in your
own way to the point where you're
saying, that's the only way I'm going to
keep doing it. You're open-minded to be
able to say, "Hey, maybe this skill set
can translate over here and and let's
give it a shot." it doesn't work out,
cool, but the work works if you do the
work. And you've done the work, and now
you've been able to see that you've got
these two consistent, predictable
pillars of content that the best part
is, don't only work for just you, they
work for anybody who's willing to do
them. And so, with that being said, I'd
love for you to kind of touch on
into the fact that you and I are
partners. And if people are struggling
in their business, and they want to just
go to a crystal clear, proven roadmap of
exactly what to do to take their
business to the next level, they could
partner with you and myself and who
enable to get our help for that. So,
ultimately, what does it look like when
somebody partners with you? Because I
know you've got a huge heart, you
genuinely care, and we just touched on
the tip of the iceberg for the
strategies that you actually have access
to in your toolkit.
Yeah, very very important to talk about
mindset, I think first, right? One of
the things that drew me to the Wolfpack
in general is not not specifically
people. And now that I'm in, there are
people that I've gravitated more you
know, you and I work very closely
together now. I'm very very happy for
that. But
you know, you see in the traditional
model of real estate a lot of times very
old-minded thinking, very close-minded
thinking, very gatekeeping thinking.
We are not about that here. We are not
about gatekeeping. We are not about
close-mindedness or oh, I'm not I'm not
going to share the secret sauce with
you.
I'll share the secret sauce with
everybody because you know what? When
you put your spin on it, it's now your
secret sauce and it's completely
different than my secret sauce. And
we're going to have a different vibe in
a tribe. And somebody's going to connect
with you more than me because you said
the thing a little bit different. You
said it in your way. So,
I love first of all that we have all of
these Value Stacks, myself, you, all
these other people in our organization
that offer so many different things.
Michael yesterday on on the YouTube like
he dropped so much knowledge on YouTube
like masterclass level stuff that people
would pay thousands of dollars to know.
And he's just like, "Hey man,
it's all free here. Just go do this."
>> is paying the thousands of dollars to
learn that. That's the craziest part.
He's in all this high-level coaching and
gives it all the way for free.
>> 100 and that says so much about the
mindset of our group. That's like and I
know I'm rambling, but I got to focus on
that.
When you are around the right-minded
people, everything becomes so much
easier for you. And you know what I
found was at a traditional brokerage, I
hit a a ceiling of productivity and I
was like, "I need to go further." There
was nobody that was willing to like
share or or or brainstorm together or
mastermind or you know, say, "Hey, this
is what's working." This is why I've
loved the Wolf Pack so much. Uh
partnering with me and partnering with
you is simple, man. Find me on
Instagram. My Instagram is my name, Matt
Thornburg. You can find my phone number
and just give me a call. My my
communication is always open. I love
helping other people.
It's funny,
you know, I don't want to be in
production in the next couple of years.
Not because I'm tired of doing
production, but because I actually love
like when I'm helping people communicate
better and have better language
uh uh skills and have better
conversations,
I get so much more fulfillment about out
of that nowadays. I love that when I get
somebody who comes back to me, they're
like, "Dude, I crushed this appointment
today and I I did what you said to do
and like the conversation was so much
easier." Like I love that, right? So, if
you have questions about social media,
about about how to communicate better,
just find me and reach out, man. Let's
have a casual conversation about where
your business is at, where you're
feeling that you're not supported,
right? This is what I think is very
important. You know, I think agents will
choose brokerages for the wrong reasons.
I think you should choose a brokerage,
the real reason you should choose a
brokerage, number one is
like are you getting the support and the
tools and the systems to do what you
want to do? Not to do what everybody
else tells you you should do, but to do
what you want to do, right?
Look for a company that gives you those
three things that also has the culture
and the mindset that is right. That's
it. That's And and
I got I'm going to sound so douchey
here. I don't think for for an agent
that wants to be successful in this day
and age, in our technology-driven
business, in our social media-driven
business, and in our AI-driven business,
I get recruitment phone calls multiple
times a week. I haven't seen another
company or organization
that provides what we provide. And I I
hate to say that like I sound like I'm
recruiting. I don't want to recruit, to
be honest. I want to attract. If you're
not happy, not feeling supported, you're
not thinking that you get your
frustrated You shouldn't be frustrated
in this business. This business is easy
when you have the right support. If
you're frustrated, you're not getting
the right support, mentorship, or
guidance. That's it.
This business is easy.
Right?
>> 100% dude.
>> guess I should rephrase that. It's not
easy, it's simple.
>> Yeah.
>> It's hard, but it's simple, right? It is
you does require the hard work. Um so
yeah man, uh specifically, I know we
alluded to my communication stuff, we're
going to talk about that later, but I
have a landing page
thornburghomegroup.com/loree
language of real estate.
You can go there and literally get the
call info. You can go to my Instagram
and connect with me. Go to my Instagram
and steal my video ideas. If you're in
Chicago, look at the videos I'm making
and make them about Chicago.
>> Yeah.
>> Dude.
We we share our knowledge here because
we want other people to succeed. I
firmly believe that we go further
together.
We all go further together. You don't
know what you don't know until somebody
else enlightens you to it. And that's
what we do at the Wolfpack. We enlighten
each other. We open each other's minds
and perspectives. We show each other how
things can be done and then we support
each other to go do it.
Like you said, Mike's paying thousands
of dollars for his YouTube coaching and
he's giving it away for free. You know,
I do I do this call every Tuesday
morning. I don't get paid for that call.
I don't I I don't get anything out of
that call except for fulfillment of
sharing my knowledge with other people
and then them telling me, "Dude, I
crushed this conversation because of
what you taught me about how to
communicate."
Like
>> 100%
>> I want other people to succeed.
>> It's amazing. And and that's what I love
about it is no dude, like it's it's
incredible to see that you, you know,
you have such a big heart and and people
have that conscious choice. And like you
say, like struggling is a choice. Like
we've helped so many people in that
situation radically transform their
business by just giving them clarity,
confidence of exactly what to do. And
you know, the coolest part is cuz nobody
really knows, but some of the stuff I'm
working on for our new training is going
to be on a completely different
capacity. And again, that's just because
we always want to stay one step ahead of
the curve. And so, guys, with that being
said, per usual, all of Matt's content
and his calendar is linked below. And
have the conversation. Explore if it's
good fit. If it is, great. If it's not,
totally okay. But at least have that
dialogue to explore is there a better
way that you could be building your
business and having a heck of a lot more
fun while doing it. So, with that being
said, Matt, make sure you guys check out
the next video we're going to do
together on communication because that
will transform everything that you do.
But dude, thank you so much again for
just sharing everything and being such
an open book as always.
>> Always, man. You're very welcome. I love
our conversations. I love the value it
brings to people. And like you said, my
calendar link is in the description. If
you're not feeling fulfilled or you're
feeling frustrated in this business,
dude, grab a half an hour time on my
calendar. We'll have a very casual, no
pressure chat. At the end of it, you're
going to walk away with more
information, which is never a bad thing,
and you're either going to find out
there's a better path and maybe, you
know, we can start building a plan for
you to get where you want to be,
or you're going to leave with some more
free, helpful information. Neither one
of those things is going to hurt, man.
Grab a time to chat.
>> There you go. Guys, with that being
said, make sure you like, comment,
subscribe so you don't miss another one,
and we'll see you in the next video.